Inventory of the Resistencia Nicaragüense records, 1983-1989
Hoover Institution Archives
Resistencia Nicaragüense records, 1983-1989.
1983-1990
92001
Resistencia Nicaragüense (Organization)
28 manuscript boxes (11.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The records pertain to an umbrella organization uniting the main components of the armed resistance to the Sandinista government in Nicaragua in the 1980s. They are comprised largely of correspondence, communiqués, clippings, memoranda, press releases, proposals, programs, and reports. Additionally, there are case files relating to legal proceedings involving some Resistencia Nicaragüense officials.
Administrative Information
Access
One box (Box 28) is closed. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Resistencia Nicaragüense (Ejercito), Hoover Institution Archives
Scope and Content of Collection
The Resistencia Nicaragüense records pertain to an umbrella organization uniting the main components of the armed resistance to the Sandinista government in Nicaragua in the 1980s. They are comprised largely of correspondence, communiqués, clippings, memoranda, press releases, proposals, programs, and reports. Additionally, there are case files relating to legal proceedings involving some Resistencia Nicaragüense officials.
Established in May 1987, Resistencia Nicaragüense succeeded an earlier coalition, Unidad Nicaragüense Opositora. As the political wing of what was generally referred to as the contra movement, Resistencia Nicaragüense was primarily concerned with public relations-disseminating information on the armed resistance, and documenting what it considered to be the repressive nature of the Sandinista government. It was also responsible for formulating policy positions for the resistance, including the elaboration of the negotiating stance of the contras in various peace talks conducted with the Nicaraguan government.
The records are arranged in the order that they were received. The first eight boxes of the records contain detailed files from the period leading up to the signing of the Sapoá Agreement between the Resistencia Nicaragüense directorate and the Nicaraguan government. These files document the mediation efforts made at the time by Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, and include proposals from both the Resistencia Nicaragüense directorate and the Sandinista leadership, as well as the text of the Sapoá Agreement. There is information on the implementation of the agreement, and the subsequent breakdown of the cease fire that had resulted from the accord.
The records also contain files relating to the case of Linder v. Calero, a lawsuit brought against four contra officials by the family of Benjamin Linder, an American aid worker killed in Nicaragua. More generally, the records include many press releases and statements issued by the directorate of Resistencia Nicaragüense, as well as a number of reports on military operations conducted by contra forces. There are internal documents that reveal various disagreements between military commanders and the political leadership of the resistance. The records also contain a substantial number of clippings relating to the Nicaraguan civil war and to other political developments in Central America.
Some of the earlier materials in the records were generated by Unidad Nicaragüense Opositora. There are also numerous materials in the records relating to the individual organizations that comprised Resistencia Nicaragüense, including the Fuerzas Democráticas Nicaragüenses (FDN) and YATAMA (Yapti Tasba Masraka Nanih Aslatakanka), a resistance group formed by Indians from the Atlantic coast of Nicaragua. There is little in the records about the various controversies relating to the Reagan administration's supplying of arms to the contras, nor is there documentation of the broader question of American financial and logistical aid to the resistance.
A separate collection of materials from the armed wing of the resistance, Ejército records, is closed, although a portion of the collection is available for use on microfilm.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Nicaragua--Politics and government--1979-1990.; Nicaragua--History--1979-1990.; Nicaragua--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Nicaragua.
Collection Contents
- Press releases, open letters, and related documents, 1989
  - January (Folder 1: 1)
  - February-March (Folder 1: 2)
  - April (Folder 1: 3)
  - May-June (Folder 1: 4)
  - July (Folder 1: 6)
  - August-September (Folder 1: 7)
- Peace agreements, 1988-1989
  - Sapoá Agreement, 1988-1989 (Folder 2: 1-6)
  - Other diplomatic initiatives, 1989 (Folder 2: 7-8)
- Press release, 1988 February 11 (Folder 3: 1)
- Summary of military activities, 1988 February 12 (Folder 3: 2-3)
- Letter from Azucena Ferrey to José Napoleon Duarte, 1988 February 12 (Folder 3: 4)
- Communiqué, 1988 February 15 (Folder 3: 5)
- Communiqué, 1988 February 16 (Folder 3: 6)
- Press release and agenda, 1988 February 17 (Folder 3: 7)
- Letter from Violeta de Chamorro to Oscar Arias Sánchez, 1988 February 18 (Folder 3: 8)
- Communiqué, 1988 February 18 (Folder 3: 9)
- Guatemala meeting, 1988 February 18 (Folder 3: 10)
- Press release, 1988 February 19 (Folder 3: 11)
- Guatemala negotiations, 1988 February 18 (Folder 3: 12)
- Proposal by Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 February 18 (Folder 3: 13)
- Communiqués, 1988 February 19 (Folder 3: 14)
- Public statement by Ramón Emilio Jiménez, 1988 February 2 (Folder 3: 15)
- Speech by President Reagan, 1988 February 2 (Folder 3: 16)
- Washington demonstration, 1988 February 2 (Folder 3: 17)
- Press release, 1988 February 5 (Folder 3: 18)
- Communiqué, 1988 February 5 (Folder 3: 19)
- Open letter to the American people, 1988 February 6 (Folder 3: 20)
- Open letter to the Japanese people, 1988 February 6 (Folder 3: 21)
- Statements by Alfonso Robelo Callejas, 1988 February 8 (Folder 3: 22-23)
- Press releases, 1988 February 9 (Folder 3: 24-25)
- Press release, 1988 February 10 (Folder 3: 26)
- Press release, 1988 January 21 (Folder 3: 27)
- Minutes of meeting, 1988 January 21 (Folder 3: 28)
- Press releases, 1988 January 22 (Folder 3: 29-30)
- Letter of resignation from Alfonso Robelo, 1988 January 27 (Folder 3: 31)
- Press release, 1988 January 28 (Folder 3: 32)
- Cease fire proposal, 1988 January 28 (Folder 3: 33)
- Sandinista proposal, 1988 January 28 (Folder 3: 34)
- Document on Sandinista strategy, 1988 (Folder 3: 35)
- Clippings relating to deaths of civilians, 1988 February (Folder 3: 36)
- Declaration by opposition parties, 1988 February 3 (Folder 3: 37)
- Press release, 1988 February 2 (Folder 3: 38)
- Declaration by Central American presidents, 1988 January 17 (Folder 3: 39)
- Communiqué, 1988 January 19 (Folder 3: 40)
- Communiqué, 1988 January 24 (Folder 3: 41)
- Press release, 1988 January 27 (Folder 3: 42)
- Letter from Daniel Ortega to Ronald Reagan, 1988 January 20 (Folder 3: 43)
- Communiqué, 1988 January 13 (Folder 3: 44)
- Statement by Alfredo César, 1988 January 13 (Folder 3: 45)
- Statement by Pedro Joaquín Chamorro, 1988 January 14 (Folder 3: 46)
- Communiqué, 1988 January 15 (Folder 3: 47)
- Transcript of press conference by Daniel Ortega, 1988 January 16 (Folder 3: 48)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 29 (Folder 3: 49)
- Letter from Aristides Sínchez to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 March 29 (Folder 3: 50)
- Message from Daniel Ortega, 1988 January 1 (Folder 3: 51)
- Press release, 1988 January 4 (Folder 3: 52)
- Press release, 1988 January 6 (Folder 3: 53)
- Communiqué, 1988 January 8 (Folder 3: 54)
- Letter from Azucena Ferrey and Adolfo Calero to Orville Schell and Aryeh Neier, 1988 January 12 (Folder 3: 55)
- Letter from Oscar Arias to Alfonso Robelo, Alfredo César, and Pedro Joaquín Chamorro, 1988 January 1 (Folder 3: 56)
- Letter from Directorate to Carlos Huembes, 1988 January 13 (Folder 3: 57)
- List of prisoners, 1988 March 26 (Folder 4: 1)
- Congressional resolution, 1988 March 19 (Folder 4: 2)
- Press release, 1988 March 29 (Folder 4: 3)
- Congressional resolution, 1988 March 30 (Folder 4: 4)
- Clipping relating to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 February 21 (Folder 4: 5)
- Summary of military activities, 1988 February 23 (Folder 4: 6)
- Letter from Daniel Ortega to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 February 23 (Folder 4: 7)
- Press release, 1988 February 24 (Folder 4: 8)
- Communiqué, 1988 February 24 (Folder 4: 9)
- Letter from Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo to Daniel Ortega, 1988 February 25 (Folder 4: 10)
- Note to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 February 29 (Folder 4: 11)
- Communiqué, 1988 February 29 (Folder 4: 12)
- Press release, 1988 March 2 (Folder 4: 13)
- Peace proposals, 1988 March (Folder 4: 14)
- Letter from Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo to Daniel Ortega, 1988 March 2 (Folder 4: 15)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 2 (Folder 4: 16)
- Statement by Norman José Miranda, 1988 March 2 (Folder 4: 17)
- Proposals for constitutional reform, 1988 (Folder 4: 18)
- Statement by Roger Ivan Villavicencio Tapía, 1988 March 2 (Folder 4: 19)
- Press release, 1988 March 3 (Folder 4: 20)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 3 (Folder 4: 21)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 6 (Folder 4: 22)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 13 (Folder 4: 23)
- Letter from Humberto Ortega to Adolfo Calero, 1988 April 13 (Folder 4: 24)
- Press release, 1988 April 15 (Folder 4: 25)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 15 (Folder 4: 26)
- Declaration of YATAMA, 1988 April 15 (Folder 4: 27)
- Press release, 1988 April 16 (Folder 4: 28)
- Press release, 1988 April 17 (Folder 4: 29)
- Operative accord, 1988 April 18 (Folder 4: 30)
- Cease fire proposal by Sandinistas, 1988 April 18 (Folder 4: 31)
- Press release, 1988 April 7 (Folder 4: 32)
- Proposal on implementation of Sapoá Agreement, 1988 April 7 (Folder 4: 33)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 April 11 (Folder 4: 34)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Roberto Ferrey, 1988 April 11 (Folder 4: 35)
- Press release, 1988 April 12 (Folder 4: 36)
- Letter to Humberto Ortega from Adolfo Calero and Pedro Joaquín Chamorro, 1988 April 13 (Folder 4: 37)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 8 (Folder 4: 38)
- Open letter to Daniel Ortega, 1988 April 7 (Folder 4: 39)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 2 (Folder 4: 40)
- Program of activities, 1988 April 5 (Folder 4: 41)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 April 6 (Folder 4: 42)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 6 (Folder 4: 43)
- Statement by Daniel Ortega, 1988 April 6 (Folder 4: 44)
- Letter from Aristides Sánchez to João Clemente Baena Soares, 1988 April 6 (Folder 4: 45)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Aristides Sánchez, 1988 April 1 (Folder 4: 46)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Jaime Morales Carazo, 1988 April 2 (Folder 4: 47)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 April 2 (Folder 4: 48)
- Letter from Humberto Ortega to Adolfo Calero, 1988 April 4 (Folder 4: 49)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 2 (Folder 4: 50)
- Communiqué, 1988 September 5 (Folder 4: 51)
- Press release, 1988 September 6 (Folder 4: 52)
- Communiqué from Daniel Ortega, 1988 March 7 (Folder 5: 1)
- Press release, 1988 March 7 (Folder 5: 2)
- Report by Horacio Ruíz, 1988 March 22 (Folder 5: 3)
- Statement by Adolfo Calero and Alfredo César, 1988 March 23 (Folder 5: 4)
- Press release, 1988 March 23 (Folder 5: 5)
- Sandinista communiqué, 1988 March 23 (Folder 5: 6)
- Statement by Secretary Shultz, 1988 March 24 (Folder 5: 7)
- Coordinara Democrática Nicaragüense communiqué, 1988 March 25 (Folder 5: 8)
- List of freed prisoners, 1988 March 25 (Folder 5: 9)
- Press release, 1988 September 7 (Folder 5: 10)
- Press release, 1988 September 8 (Folder 5: 11)
- Interview with Adolfo Calero y Roberto Ferrey, 1988 September 8 (Folder 5: 12)
- Statement by José Antonio Tijerino, 1988 September 14 (Folder 5: 13)
- Communiqué, 1988 September 9 (Folder 5: 14)
- Press release by Coordinara Democrática Nicaragüense, 1988 September 9 (Folder 5: 15)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 September 10 (Folder 5: 16)
- Press release, 1988 September 12 (Folder 5: 17)
- Statement by labor sector, 1988 September 14 (Folder 5: 18)
- Press release, 1988 September 14 (Folder 5: 19)
- Statement by Haydee Marin, 1988 September 14 (Folder 5: 20)
- Speech by Enrique Bolaños Geyer, 1988 September 15 (Folder 5: 21)
- Letter from directors to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 September 1 (Folder 5: 22)
- Letter to Alfredo César from Miskito representatives, 1988 September 2 (Folder 5: 23)
- Transcript of press conference, 1988 September 1 (Folder 5: 24)
- Press release, 1988 September 2 (Folder 5: 25)
- Acción Democrática Nicaragüense communiqué, 1988 September 3 (Folder 5: 26)
- Open letter from the Comité Sindical de Obreros y Campesinos Nicaragüenses en el Exilio (CSOCANE), 1988 August (Folder 5: 27)
- Report on cease fire violations, 1988 October 7 (Folder 5: 28)
- Communiqué, 1988 August 23 (Folder 5: 29)
- Communiqué, 1988 September 1 (Folder 5: 30)
- Communiqué, 1988 September 15 (Folder 5: 31)
- Article on election law, 1988 August 25 (Folder 5: 32)
- Press release, 1988 August 26 (Folder 5: 33)
- Reports on Costa Rican ship detained by Nicaraguan government, 1988 August 26 (Folder 5: 34)
- Announcement of press conference, 1988 August 29 (Folder 5: 35)
- Statement by Enrique Bermúdez, 1988 May 3 (Folder 5: 36)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 18 (Folder 5: 37)
- Letter from Directorate to Humberto Ortega, 1988 April 7 (Folder 5: 38)
- Pronouncement by Conservative party, 1988 April 29 (Folder 5: 39)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 29 (Folder 5: 40)
- Proposal by Nicaraguan government, 1988 April 30 (Folder 5: 41)
- Letter from Directorate to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 April 30 (Folder 5: 42)
- Resolution of Verification Commission of the Sapoá Agreement, 1988 April 30 (Folder 5: 43)
- Press release, 1988 April 29 (Folder 5: 44)
- Reports and other documents relating to a visit to Managua by a delegation from Resistencia Nicaragüense, 1988 April 28-30 (Folder 5: 45)
- Summary of seminar on the Nicaraguan economy, 1988 March 8 (Folder 6: 1)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 8 (Folder 6: 2)
- Memorandum, 1988 March 9 (Folder 6: 3)
- Statement by Adolfo Calero, 1988 March 10 (Folder 6: 4)
- Summary of military activities, 1988 March 11 (Folder 6: 5)
- YATAMA communiqué, 1988 March 11 (Folder 6: 6)
- Communiqué from Daniel Ortega, 1988 March 12 (Folder 6: 7)
- Press release from the Nicaraguan Association for Human Rights, 1988 May 4 (Folder 6: 8)
- Communiqué from Congreso Permanente de los Trabajadores, 1988 May 3 (Folder 6: 9)
- Press release, 1988 May 4 (Folder 6: 10)
- Communiqué, 1988 May 5 (Folder 6: 11)
- Press release, 1988 May 5 (Folder 6: 12)
- Letter from YATAMA to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 May 6 (Folder 6: 13)
- YATAMA communiqué, 1988 May 6 (Folder 6: 14)
- La Prensa editorial, 1988 May 5 (Folder 6: 15)
- Press release, 1988 May 9 (Folder 6: 16)
- Communiqué, 1988 May 7 (Folder 6: 17)
- Memorandum, 1988 May 10 (Folder 6: 18)
- Press release, 1988 May 12 (Folder 6: 19)
- Congressional letter to Daniel Ortega, 1988 May 12 (Folder 6: 20)
- Communiqué, 1988 May 15 (Folder 6: 21)
- Press release, 1988 May 16 (Folder 6: 22)
- YATAMA communiqué, 1988 May 18 (Folder 6: 23)
- La Prensa editorial, 1988 May 17 (Folder 6: 24)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Robert Ferrey, 1988 May 18 (Folder 6: 25)
- Communiqué from Daniel Ortega, 1988 May 18 (Folder 6: 26)
- Memorandum from Robert Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 May 18 (Folder 6: 27)
- Transcript of press conference held by Alfredo César, 1988 May 19 (Folder 6: 28)
- Press release, 1988 May 19 (Folder 6: 29)
- Homily delivered by Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 April 18 (Folder 6: 30)
- Transcript of press conference held by Directorate, 1988 April 19 (Folder 6: 31)
- Article by Adolfo Calero, 1988 April 21 (Folder 6: 32)
- Transcript of press conference held by Directorate and civic opposition, 1988 April 25 (Folder 6: 33)
- New York Times article, 1988 April 26 (Folder 6: 34)
- Communiqué, 1988 April 26 (Folder 6: 35)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Jaime Morales Carazo, 1988 March 25 (Folder 6: 36)
- Press release, 1988 April 27 (Folder 6: 37)
- Declaration by Movimiento Social Demócrata Nicaragüense, 1988 April 27 (Folder 6: 38)
- Carta de Miguel d'Escoto Brockmann to João Clemente Baena Soares, 1988 April 27 (Folder 6: 39)
- Press release, 1988 April 29 (Folder 6: 40)
- Letter from Leda Sánchez de Parrales to Humberto Ortega, 1988 April 29 (Folder 6: 41)
- Letter from YATAMA to Directorate, 1988 June 27 (Folder 6: 42)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Humberto Ortega, 1988 June 25 (Folder 6: 43)
- YATAMA communiqué, 1988 June 27 (Folder 6: 44)
- Transcript of Directorate press conference, 1988 May 4 (Folder 6: 45)
- Press release, 1988 July 11 (Folder 6: 46)
- Interview with Pedro Joaquín Chamorro, 1988 July 11 (Folder 6: 47)
- Press releases, 1988 June 29 (Folder 6: 48-49)
- Resolutions of Verification Commission of the Sapoá Agreement, 1988 June 28-30 (Folder 6: 50-53)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Humberto Ortega, 1988 June 27 (Folder 6: 54)
- Letter from Humberto Ortega to Adolfo César, 1988 June 24 (Folder 6: 55)
- Press release, 1988 June 24 (Folder 6: 56)
- Communiqué from Congreso Permanente de los Trabajadores, 1988 May 1 (Folder 6: 57)
- Speech by Daniel Ortega, 1988 May 1 (Folder 6: 58)
- Statement by Adolfo Calero, 1988 June 24 (Folder 6: 59)
- Transcript of press conference, 1988 July 8 (Folder 6: 60)
- Article by Adolfo Calero, 1988 July 5 (Folder 6: 61)
- YATAMA communiqué, 1988 July 20 (Folder 6: 62)
- Letter from Alfredo César to George Volsky, 1988 July 6 (Folder 6: 63)
- Communiqué, 1988 July 7 (Folder 6: 64)
- Press release, 1988 July 8 (Folder 6: 65)
- Transcript of press conference, 1988 June 22 (Folder 7: 1)
- Communiqué from dissidents, 1988 June 22 (Folder 7: 2)
- Statements by Adolfo Calero, Azucena Ferrey, and Aristides Sánchez, 1988 June 23 (Folder 7: 3)
- Press release, 1988 June 23 (Folder 7: 4)
- Letter from Violeta Chamorro to Jimmy Carter, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 5)
- Communiqué from Congreso Permanente de los Trabajadores, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 6)
- Patriotic accord, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 7)
- Coordinara Democrática Nicaragüense communiqué, 1988 June 21 (Folder 7: 8)
- Communiqué from political parties, 1988 June 21 (Folder 7: 9)
- Sandinista communiqué, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 10)
- Letter from Roberto Ferrey to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo and João Clemente Baena Soares, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 11)
- Letter from Humberto Ortega to João Clemente Baena Soares, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 12)
- Communiqué, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 13)
- YATAMA communiqué, 1988 June 20 (Folder 7: 14)
- Communiqué, 1988 June 13 (Folder 7: 15)
- Transcript of press conference, 1988 June 14 (Folder 7: 16)
- Press release, 1988 June 14 (Folder 7: 17)
- Press release, 1988 June 17 (Folder 7: 18)
- Communiqué, 1988 June 17 (Folder 7: 19)
- Pronouncement by Conservative party, 1988 June 18 (Folder 7: 20)
- Letter from Humberto Ortega to Alfredo César, 1988 June 19 (Folder 7: 21)
- Press release, 1988 August 30 (Folder 7: 22)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Alfredo César, 1988 August 30 (Folder 7: 23)
- Letter from general staff to Directorate, 1988 August (Folder 7: 24)
- Press release, 1988 August 31 (Folder 7: 25)
- Bloque Opositor del Sur communiqué, 1988 August 20 (Folder 7: 26)
- Press releasees, 1988 August 18-19 (Folder 7: 27-28)
- Points of agreement of the progressive center, 1988 August 19 (Folder 7: 29)
- Letter from Adolfo Calero and Aristide Sánchez to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo and João Clemente Baena Soares, 1988 August 12 (Folder 7: 30)
- Press releases, 1988 August 10, 12 and 17 (Folder 7: 31-33)
- Article by Adolfo Calero, 1988 August 10 (Folder 7: 34)
- Interview with Ramiro Gurdián, 1988 August 11 (Folder 7: 35)
- Statement by Oscar Arias Sánchez, 1988 August 5 (Folder 7: 36)
- Coordinara Democrática Nicaragüense communiqué, 1988 August 5 (Folder 7: 37)
- Press release, 1988 August 8 (Folder 7: 38)
- Letter from imprisoned opposition leaders to the Nicaraguan public, 1988 August 5 (Folder 7: 39)
- Letter from Oscar Arias Sánchez to Daniel Ortega, 1988 August 5 (Folder 7: 40)
- Letter from Directorate to Central American presidents, 1988 August 2 (Folder 7: 41)
- Communiqués, 1988 August 3 (Folder 7: 42-43)
- Report on Sandinista attack, 1988 August 4 (Folder 7: 44)
- Press release, 1988 August 4 (Folder 7: 45)
- Annex to communiqué, 1988 July 26 (Folder 7: 46)
- Statement by Vinicio Cerezo Arévalo, 1988 August 1 (Folder 7: 47)
- Communiqué, 1988 July 26 (Folder 7: 48)
- Remarks by Wycliffe Diego, 1988 July 28 (Folder 7: 49)
- Communiqué, 1988 July 29 (Folder 7: 50)
- Press release, 1988 July 26 (Folder 7: 51)
- Letter from Directorate to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo and João Clemente Baena Soares, 1988 July 26 (Folder 7: 52)
- Communiqué, 1988 July 26 (Folder 7: 53)
- Letter from Enrique Bermúdez to Directorate, 1988 July 20 (Folder 7: 54)
- Press release, 1988 July 21 (Folder 7: 55)
- List of commanders, 1988 July 25 (Folder 7: 56)
- Statement by Adolfo Calero, 1988 July 12 (Folder 7: 57)
- Press release, 1988 July 12 (Folder 7: 58)
- List of detainees, 1988 July 13 (Folder 7: 59)
- Press releases, 1988 July 15 and July 19 (Folder 7: 60-61)
- Press release, 1988 March 14 (Folder 8: 1)
- Communiqué from journalists in exile, 1988 March 14 (Folder 8: 2)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Jaime Morales Carazo, 1988 March 14 (Folder 8: 3)
- Memorandum from Jaime Morales Carazo to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 March 14 (Folder 8: 4)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Jaime Morales Carazo, 1988 March 15 (Folder 8: 5)
- Press release, 1988 March 15 (Folder 8: 6)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 16 (Folder 8: 7)
- Sandinista proposal, 1988 March 21 (Folder 8: 8)
- Press release, 1988 March 21 (Folder 8: 9)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 2 (Folder 8: 10)
- Letter from Daniel Ortega to Cardinal Miguel Obando y Bravo, 1988 March 2 (Folder 8: 11)
- Communiqué, 1988 March 21 (Folder 8: 12)
- Interview with Adolfo Calero, 1988 March 21 (Folder 8: 13)
- Communiqué from opposition parties, 1988 March 21 (Folder 8: 14)
- Articles and reports relating to negotiations in Sapoá, 1988 March 21-23 (Folder 8: 15)
- Proposal from Directorate to Nicaraguan government, 1988 March 22 (Folder 8: 16)
- Text of Sapoá Agreement, 1988 March 23 (Folder 8: 17)
- Communiqués, 1988 May 20 (Folder 8: 18)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Roberto Ferrey, 1988 May 20 (Folder 8: 19)
- Memorandum from Roberto Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 May 20 (Folder 8: 20)
- Letter from Victor Hugo Tinoco to Roberto Ferrey, 1988 May 22 (Folder 8: 21)
- Communiqué, 1988 May 23 (Folder 8: 22)
- Communiqué from Nicaraguan government, 1988 May 23 (Folder 8: 23)
- Communiqué, 1988 May 23 (Folder 8: 24)
- Statement by Ronald Reagan, 1988 May 24 (Folder 8: 25)
- Memorandum from Roberto Ferrey to Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 May 25 (Folder 8: 26)
- Press release, 1988 May 26 (Folder 8: 27)
- Transcript of press conference held by Victor Hugo Tinoco, 1988 May 26 (Folder 8: 28)
- Sandinista proposal, 1988 May 26 (Folder 8: 29)
- List of members of Managua delegation, 1988 May 26 (Folder 8: 30)
- Proposal made by Directorate to Nicaraguan government, 1988 May 26 (Folder 8: 31)